welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where we go here and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
get this on screen alright does this
work you guys see the screen yeah and by
the way you can also go through the link
you should be open on Google Drive yes
so how about scroll my screen ok it does
work yes so anyway what is a pandemic so
I think most people aren't really
thinking about the the concept of
pandemic in the right way but they're
too focused on this idea of the virus
there have too much of a viral kind of
tunnel vision like they think the Canada
depend them it's only about a virus and
a lot of people would criticize but
people who take the virus seriously and
just say well the virus is only killing
whatever amount of people but really a
pandemic isn't just a virus it's like
everything that's surrounding the whole
situation like if the virus didn't exist
in the first place all these other
things that's happening in the world
also probably wouldn't happen or it
would at least hop in a very different
way so you have to really consider the
cascading effects and how which changes
the shape of the world in general and I
think part of the reason why people
think this way is the modern science has
shown showed us that diseases come from
specific pathogens and it's really kind
of ironic how a lot of these it's like
so-called anti science people really
cling onto this fact we basically say oh
we get this thing that happened they
couldn't make these memes where they
show for example person who died in a
car crash I said this must be a corona
tough but actually it kind of is because
it's like historically the basically
like any crazy thing that happens during
this whole time period of the plague
trying to consider part of the play
people don't really know what's causing
the plague so like anything that's crazy
that's going on especially like some
sort of illness they think it's part the
plague and in modernity really there's
even more crazy cascading effects which
we'll get to later like hearing so look
at all these possible just skating
effects of a pandemic but we don't just
have death from the illness we also have
all these other potential issues and I
guess I'm not gonna read out all from
you guys can take a look but basically
there are all sorts of economic issues
which necessarily come with the the
pandemic like whether we have a lockdown
or not if people are sick they're
zombies so economic issues as as well
and and also like the surveillance issue
like that's a problem
like do we really want to do contact
tracing maybe maybe not it kind of
depends on the situation and the social
unrest that we are currently seeing for
for example like the black lives matter
situation and also like for the protests
against the lockdown a couple weeks ago
there was all kind of related to the
plane itself but these things would not
manifest the way they did if the virus
did exist in the first place
right right let's go back to here and
look at this quote at the top so
basically
when the plague happens they also brings
in like a warts contemplate which like
that it kind of it basically implies the
mimetic contagion which means basically
all obvious like social means that
people are spreading and the emotional
but but people's emotions are also very
viral and also ideas are also very viral
those things spread during a pandemic in
a way that's also very uncontrollable
because when people are already freaking
out about the virus there Gus like all
these things are - sorry Paulo on
cascade together and we so basically
when you look at people who are Preppers
prepping for the pandemic you you have
all these ton of stereotypes that go
into your mind but really when you put
for pandemic it's not just about the
typical proper stuff I mean that stuff a
lot of it helps - definitely but we also
have to consider all these other factors
here that typical Preppers might not
really think about
so our focus today is the ball security
aspect of it and I think there's a
couple issues that are being brushed
over a lot by just most people who
discuss the topic especially the media
really doesn't really give any attention
to this as well as there's a lot of
sketchy things going on with
institutions such as the who just kind
of complete denying these possibilities
and actually even nature itself the
nature but you guys probably know about
nature the research publications are
usually pretty credible but it's really
weird at the or origin of the pandemic
and basically immediately in January
that basically for these disclaimers on
their papers saying yo I know we wrote
the stuff about the potential dangers of
these types of experiments before or
like the problems with ball safety at
certain labs in China before party just
completely ignore that don't don't think
that the virus came from there at all it
definitely came from many of what market
I was a very suspicious narrative and I
wrote an article an essay uh probably
it's a it's probably more a two month
ago but gotta wait actually it's been
like yeah it's probably more like three
month ago but it got published probably
early April where I discussed several
possible scenarios where it came from it
could come from a lot but it's not
necessarily intentionally released ball
walking like thing like that
but there's so many possible mistakes
that you can make in a lab where a virus
can become more dangerous and then we go
and like I feel like even my essay was
not that comprehensive like if you watch
videos by Brett Weinstein
Heather Haines and then also a couple
videos by Chris Martenson they bring out
a whole bunch of other fog
haven't even discovered and haven't even
talked about in my in my paper and you
know I would definitely recommend you
guys do check them out after after this
so some topics they talk about are
potential dangerous experiments like
this accelerated evolution and creation
of chimera viruses and Daniel functional
research and one thing I really like to
stress is that these vaccine labs can
also be converted to ball woven labs
they're called
basically fuel use research that's the
technical term for it it's something can
be used for both military and serve a
civilian civilian purposes like when you
look at lab it has all these equipment
it's not clear what it's going to use to
it but you can easily claim that you're
researching a vaccine and all of a
sudden in a couple weeks shifted your
training Apollo them and part of that
problem is gain-of-function research and
get a function basically means you give
a virus more functionality so for
example previously it couldn't infect
humans or previously it wasn't airborne
but let's make it airborne and a lot of
times the researchers will claim that
this is for kind of simulating what will
happen in case something bad happens but
that kind of increases the risk of
something actually bad happening itself
so it's not like a paradox
so during the preparation period we can
actually end up creating a risk that
wouldn't have existed in the first place
and I really like this diagram brett
Weinstein and AMA this is one of their
podcasts so they basically outlined what
they think is the most possible origin
the virus and I basically under %
universe stuff they wanting to do a lot
of great details about how things might
happen
and basically what you see here is they
think there's a 90% Hospital came from
the lab and it's most likely an
accidental escape but like when they
accidentally escapes there's a lot of
possibilities for how could an accident
like a cookie ball walking that's it but
it's probably slightly possibility it
could also be pure research that also
for designing some sort of vaccine for
some other illness before where these
there's tons of types of research that
unless you're in that specific specific
field you can't even imagine whether
they're trying to study so that so here
are some points that Bart Weinstein
Heather had actually discussed for
implications if hope at 19 was ball
what's made in a lab so the lab
environment is very different from a
organic environment outside what happens
in a lab is not always the same
condition as what happens outside of lab
inside a lab you can see a lot faster
mutations because that's how the lab was
designed so there's this evolutionary
pressure to mutate faster if it
originated from a lab and what we see
currently is there's all sorts of crazy
mutations many many strengths of Cova 19
and you see all these reports of
completely different types of symptoms
coming from different parts of the world
so that could be an indicator that was
from a lab environment and this is also
something that we should watch out for
and pay more close attention to
another thing we know this is that the
coronavirus it's really bad at
transmitting outside but it transmits
like very well inside which is another
indicator am a head of came from the lab
lobbying by amazing doors and also
excuse me not under like a lot of light
like often the labs are having basically
their basic dark a lot of times so that
could be an indicator and well that
could be a possible reason why the
chrono virus gets killed so quickly by
UV light I mean it's not like a
guarantee that's that's the case but
it's just it just kinda explains why we
think there's a good 90% possibility
that they came from the lab that's part
of but like this is part of reasoning
and but just because it doesn't transmit
well outside currently doesn't mean it
might not later because since the virus
mutates extremely quickly and it wasn't
adapted to an outdoor environment before
it could very well mutate in a way where
it can adapt to it outdoor transmission
later so we need to watch out for that
and lastly like I mentioned before we we
really need to pay close attention to
these types of risky research such as
gamma function and accelerated evolution
and question why do they even exist at
all
and here's some links to possible
questionable research like one story
recently was a monkey stole some blood
samples from a lab technician in India
like that's that's a pretty ridiculous
kind of almost humorous situation but it
is funny what goes on in labs not all
the researchers are responsible and even
if they all
to be responsible sometimes they make
mistakes and when you deal with
dangerous pathogens crazy stuff like
that just might happen and I could get
released out into the general public and
in fact I've wanted innocent people say
very likely possibility and when you do
research like infecting monkeys
intentionally to see how to observe the
virus that's also very questionable
because anytime you attract a animal you
increase risk of developing new
mutations that might make the disease
more dangerous so everything about just
like the fact that we're even doing
research on monkeys at all during this
pandemic it's kind of questionable like
a lot of the things we do for the
purpose of trying to make the situation
better and might just be making the
situation worse and another thing is
like crisper and possible ball weapons
in the future but that's fun I like more
down the line and I would say it's not a
current primary threat but we have to
think about the possibility of what if
someone gets funding to do some sort of
research for that's intended to be a
treatment for Kovan 19 but actually
they're just trading for weapons in
their lives now I don't know if that's
actually happening but we could end up
going down it's like very dystopian kind
of kind of feedback loop or you have one
pandemic and then during this pandemic
while people are trying to find cures
some of those people who are supposedly
trying to find cures just end up
training next pandemic and just the
cycle repeats but hopefully that's not
what's happening but it's also hard to
prevent it or even like find out about
it even if that's really happening so
that's something we need to think about
and I don't even have a good solution
to that so what kind of action can we
actually take so I have a couple
proposals and I feel like most of those
probably will not be implemented but
they're interesting to think about for
example why do we have just one
healthcare system why don't we have two
healthcare systems like currently we
just assume all diseases are treated
equal but or not but some of our some of
them are contagious some of them some
are not but you can't really you
probably shouldn't treat a contagious
disease in the same way as a non
contagious disease like a non contagious
disease you should be able to handle in
like a private system and this is easy
should be fairly normally distributed
but the contagious disease scales up
excellent exponentially and it's
basically a threat to public good it's
very distinct from a non contagious
disease like if you have a non
contagious disease it doesn't really
affect anyone else but if you have a
contagious disease that's a threat to
national security that's a threat to
everyone else around you so it really
calls for a completely different type of
response but most doctors who are very
good at dealing with non contagious
diseases they're not really prepared for
like a full-scale endemic and we're
contes currently seen that in hospitals
so if we have two separate healthcare
systems one that's like for the purpose
of preparing for about security threats
I think that'd be a good thing however
that might just be you told me I'm
thinking because we have institutions
that are supposed to deal with these
things already like the CDC and the who
they're also kind of failing so who
knows and like I said before roughly
question the funding of certain types of
research and why do they even exist in
the first place in fact the head of CDC
from a couple years ago I think was like
2014 he was questioning why some of
these follow safety level for labs even
exist and
maybe we should just cut them down to
your only few home rather than however
many have currently and just minimizing
general comorbidities in public health
is something we should also be doing
like decreasing for example eating
healthier to decrease or easily and
heart disease and general at the
education of a public our boss security
and ball safety yes so so basically my
own solution for preparing for the for
future about security threats is that I
just create a new website I guess I'm
not make it into like official company
pretty soon I'm calling a boreal green
which basically my intention is to do
preparation plans for various types of
risks for private individuals and
families and I just we'll see how that
turns out hopefully this is something
more people what we do
all right questions cool so I'm gonna
stop sharing your screen cool I just put
in the chat box I'm like I looked at the
boreal green website look cool we gotta
get these guys on the stove I'm like oh
okay
looks like we already did it's your
website yeah opened up some kind of
collaboration with you on that maybe a
boreal green section de stoah so I was
thinking usually we do like formal q and
A's but since we have a smaller group
today and I feel a little bit more
informal mood I'm gonna stop the record
right now we can post that PowerPoint on
the YouTube and we'll have a discussion
so I'll stop right now